<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SysAdmin on Palimpsest</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SysAdmin on Palimpsest</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chroot SFTP Setup</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/chroot-sftp-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/chroot-sftp-setup/</guid>
      <description>Scenario: Callimachus works at Miskatonic University. Callimachus is working on a project that requires the placement of data files onto a remote server owned by Permissible Data Corp. (PDC). PDC will be processing the files with an automated script and returning them to Callimachus.&#xA;You&amp;rsquo;ll need some users that will only be able to perform chrooted SFTP. You&amp;rsquo;ll probably want to place them into a group for simplfied administration.&#xA;#create SFTP only group groupadd sftponly Since we&amp;rsquo;ll be using this SFTP user group to allow some of our libraries to upload files for automated processing, we&amp;rsquo;ll call the SFTP directory /incoming, to identify the functional role of the directory in the automated processing chain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cron</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/cron/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/cron/</guid>
      <description>Scheduler Basics minute:hour:day-of-month:month:day-of-week /command/to/execute.sh&#xA;Field Values Notes Minute 0-59 Hour 0-23 Day of Month 1-31 Month 1-12 Day Of Week 0-6 [0 is Sunday] Common Commands w/ Cron crontab -l # List current Linux user&amp;#39;s crontab entries crontab -u &amp;lt;username&amp;gt; -l # List other Linux user&amp;#39;s crontan entries crontab -e # Edit crontab entries crontab /path/to/cronjobs.txt # Load cron jobs from file Examples of Crontab Entries Execute job every ten minutes */10 * * * * /path/to/command.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expanding Volumes</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/expand_volumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/expand_volumes/</guid>
      <description>At some point, you&amp;rsquo;re going to run out of space and need to provision some additional storage.&#xA;Steps:&#xA;Expand Volume Capacity Expand Partition to Volume Capacity Extend Filesystem to the size of partition You&amp;rsquo;ll need to know a few things like:&#xA;What block devices are available? lsblk What filesystem am I using on a partition? file -s /dev/sda1 lsblk -f blkid What is the current capacity of storage in the filesystem?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>fail2ban</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/fail2ban/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/fail2ban/</guid>
      <description>Common Commands List Active Jails: fail2ban-client status Show Banned IPs in sshd Jail: fail2ban-client status sshd Manually Unban an IP from a Jail: fail2ban-client set {jail name} unbanip {ip address} Manually Ban an IP to a Jail: fail2ban-client set {jail name} banip {ip address} </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IPMI</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/ipmi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/ipmi/</guid>
      <description>Dell Poweredge R510 is LOUD! Make it quiter with IMPI&#xA;IPMI (Intelligent Platform Management Interface) is an open standard for monitoring, logging, recovery, inventory, and control of hardware that is implemented independent of the main CPU, BIOS, and OS.&#xA;ipmitool&#xA;IPMI-over-LAN must be enabled apt-get install lm-sensors ipmitool # This command will enable manual fan control ipmitool raw 0x30 0x30 0x01 0x00 # This command will control all fans, where ## is 00 to 64, which is mapped to 0% to 100% ipmitool raw 0x30 0x30 0x02 0xff 0x## # If you really want the IPMI specification</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LVM</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/lvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/lvm/</guid>
      <description>References Kernel Device Naming LVM Anatomy LVM Storage Management is divided into three parts: Physical Volumes (PV) – Actual disks or disk partitions (e.g. /dev/sda, /dev/sda2) Volume Groups (VG) – Physical volumes are combined into volume groups. (e.g. VolGroup1 = /dev/sda + /dev/sdb2) Logical Volumes (LV) – Volume groups are divided into logical volumes (e.g. VolGroup1 = LogicalVol1/data, LogicalVol2/home) Commands Display Disk Information&#xA;fdisk -l Display LVM Mapping&#xA;lvmdiskscan Display Physical Volumes</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Packages</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/packages/</guid>
      <description>Intro What is a Package? An archive file format containing source code, executable files, and metadata used by a package manager.&#xA;What is a Package Manager? A tool to manage installed applications, automatically compute dependencies, and figure out what things should occur to install packages.&#xA;Debian-based (Debian, Ubuntu) Package Format .deb package format .snap (single, compressed filesystem)&#xA;Package Manager dpkg - can install .deb directly apt - works with software repos</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sed &amp; awk</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/sed_awk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/sed_awk/</guid>
      <description>sed (stream editor) To perform an operation, use sed -i; otherwise, sed performs a dry-run.&#xA;You got 60+ logrotate configuration files in /etc/logrotate.d and you need to add the delaycompress directive, after the compress directive, to each of the files. The name of each configuration file that needs to be updated begins with ezproxy_. No problem!&#xA;sed &amp;#39;/compress/a\ delaycompress&amp;#39; ezproxy_* You&amp;rsquo;ve got 60+ Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt certificate .conf files that you need to increase the delay for propogation of the DNS TXT file challenge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSH</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/ssh/</guid>
      <description> Generate Keys ed25519 ssh-keygen -t ed25519 Use an SSH config file: ~/.ssh/config </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSL</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/ssl/</guid>
      <description>The private key used to generate a CSR needs to match the private .key file placed on the server to match the .crt file.&#xA;X509 File Extensions Extension Description .der Binary DER encoded certificates. These files may also bear the CER or the CRT extension. .pem Extension is used for different types of X.509v3 files which contain ASCII (Base64) armored data prefixed with a “—– BEGIN …” line. .crt Used for certificates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SysAdmin Tasks</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/sysadmin_tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/sysadmin_tasks/</guid>
      <description>Convert PuTTY SSH2 Public Key to OpenSSH ssh-keygen -if ssh2publickey.pub &amp;gt;&amp;gt; opensshpublickey.pub Identify Responding Server curl -s -I sts.psychiatrist.com|sed -n &amp;#39;s/^S[erv]*: //p&amp;#39; Byte Order Mark (BOM) When EZproxy configuration files are edited in Microsoft NotePad, EZproxy will complain - upon restart - about the single byte character ï»¿ that begins the config.txt file. EZproxy expects UTF-8 encoding that does not start with a non-ASCII byte, like a BOM.&#xA;Using vim, does current file have a BOM?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UFW</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/ufw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313///palimpsest/docs/notebooks/sysadmin/ufw/</guid>
      <description>Intro The default firewall configuration tool for Ubuntu is ufw. Developed to ease iptables firewall configuration, ufw provides a user-friendly way to create an IPv4 or IPv6 host-based firewall.&#xA;Once a rule is matched the others will not be evaluated. Putting the specific rules first and any generic rules second is expected. As rules change you may need to delete old rules to ensure that new rules are put in the proper order</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
